Oh yeah.
OK, let me share.
So Ria,
I checked with Swam in the morning.
So yesterday she told that you would be
implementing the historical SO pending
design implementation on ABCS,
historical catch upload and first time
incremental load, OK,
Upon giving all the KT to you after the
reverse engineering,
you will be taking that part, right?
But she asked me to add the details in
the LLD and lose it.
So I've just started that.
OK, it is incomplete.
Apart from that,
I'll give you all the details in a in a
high level OK today.
So I have already shared this link with
you, right?
So you already know audit balance
framework which we are using as a common
reusable framework across all source
systems,
across all exerts for auditing purpose
and doing the error,
for error handling and also for balance
reconstruction cheques.
OK.
And and we have the restartability and
rerun capabilities we have incorporated
in this code.
So first,
if you look at the ABC data model,
open this data model.
So there are two kinds of tables,
APC metadata and APC runtime tables.
Whatever tables that are highlighted in
red are metadata tables and green are
runtime tables.
Let let's go through each and every table.
OK here batch metadata job metadata,
ITIL data injection job.
OK.
Is it fine now?
Yeah.
So here in this data model,
all PKFKS are connected properly.
So if you want to check the relationship
between these tables,
you can go through this flow diagram.
So we have in as part of Zone 2,
Zone 3 ABC framework,
we have batch metadata, job metadata,
ETL data integration metadata,
job role masters,
job role assignment table and balance
reconciliation metadata.
So these are our metadata tables and as
part of runtime tables we have batch run
stats, job run stats,
job role execution log and job run stats,
balance reconciliation stats and job role
error detail.
OK, let's go go now.
Let's get a little information of all
these tables.
So in ABC table,
all the metadata tables should be loaded
first with all the table and batch level
details.
And also Dixie cheques, balance cheques,
whatever we we want to perform,
we have to make entries in all the IDC
metadata table.
First one is batch metadata table.
This batch metadata table is used to
configure batch level information.
OK.
It stores master information for each
batch include batch identification,
active status, source domain,
everything it it will have let's look
always.
So batch ID,
Batch ID is the your primary key of this
table.
It will be auto incremented value as per
the detail in Aurora and batch name.
So we are following this is the batch
name assigned to our batch.
So we are following this is the Joan name
after that batch and then source name and
domain name.
So Joan we are this is the example for
CMPM broker globe.
Joan we are load we are loading in Joan 2
batch after CMPM is the source broker is
the domain name.
So this is this is the format that we
have to follow for batch name and then
for batch description this is the
description provide to get the high level
purpose of this batch.
This batch is used to load from CMPM to
CMPM to broker data domain in joint.
So we just need to replace the source
name and domain name if we want to use
and also the to name if we want to use
for any other batch and this indicates
the.
If this indicates whether this batch is
active or not, is active and then.
So if it is not active,
then what will happen if If we don't want
to run this,
then we can what is then we can
deactivate this batch.
If we don't want to run this batch.
Suppose I'm putting entry as in OK, right?
And I'm, I'm figuring that batch,
then what will happen to that?
Will it or what will happen?
Sorry, I didn't get you properly.
What what is the question?
Do you so suppose the batch for that
batch I'm marking it as in OK and then
I'm triggering the batch then what will
happen it it won't get executed.
So like will it get in and out or like
what will happen?
It won't execute it.
So while we are bringing the batch ID,
there is a philtre is active within the
logic.
I'll show you that tomorrow.
OK,
let let's have this question noted in
your notes.
We can look into this tomorrow,
but will be applied in the logic itself.
So once we triggered the like to get the
batch task flow using the parameter
values provided in the static parameter
file,
it will try to get the batch ID right.
If the is active flag is N then it won't
get the batch ID if it if it doesn't get
the batch ID,
no entry will be made in the batch.
So if there is no entry no no job run
will happen.
OK.
And then e-mail ID is the e-mail ID which
would be provided here for notifications
like it we are not choosing it directly
anywhere but we are just providing this
as of now.
Maybe in future if we want to plug in
this e-mail ID somewhere like in the
notifications,
we have two plug in there and source name
is the CMPM name of the source domain
name, application name,
application layer name.
So here as as part of June 2,
June 3 batch we should provide source
name, domain name,
application layer name and target zone.
So we are using these 4 fields to fetch
the batch ID from this metadata table.
While for a batch room.
So these 4 fields should be populated
which one's source name, domain name,
application name or source layer?
No, no source name, domain name,
application layer name, target zone.
OK we don't need to provide.
As of now we are not populating any value
to application name so we are keeping it
as null.
OK so is there any specific Firefox for
maybe there?
This is being used by June 1 table June 1
team but it's an optional fail for June 2
OK and then application source batch ID.
So for our broker domain we are dependent
on CMPM load so it's batch ID.
We have to provide the batch ID of that
table OK and target zone.
So broker domain is in zone 2.
So we have given zone load frequency if
it is daily give it is daily.
Whatever the frequency that that this
batch load should happen,
we have to provide like that daily by
applications holds batch ID.
From where I'm getting this which one
application applications holds batch ID?
We will get it from the same batch
metadata table using the fields which are
used by the zone.
One thing so as far as I know,
they're using source name, domain name,
source name,
domain name to get the batch ID in June 1.
Their ABC framework is following that to
get a unique batch ID from the batch
metadata table.
So we should understand what is the
source name and domain name that our zone
1 force batch is using.
So based upon that, we can fetch this.
OK, so suppose you are building something,
some new mapping and all right then like
do you reach out to the zone one team or
like how do you proceed with this?
Yeah, yeah.
So for example for CCO,
we are not sure which batch should we
consider from June 1.
We know that source tables.
So we I just what I did is I just queried
using my source table name in job run
stats OK and then I found one mail ID.
Using that mail ID I reached out to that
person and asked about the details how
they have loaded this table source table
using which batch.
So based upon that information I I got
the batch ID using source name,
domain name and also they're using
application layer name also I guess raw
stage 2 something and for CCO source name
is CCO,
domain name is underwriting CCO and
application layer name is raw stage 2.
Based upon these three fields,
I got the batch ID corresponding and also
using the same ABC tables only they are
also using the same ABC tables but their
framework is different from us.
But all the tables like metadata tables,
sometimes everything is there.
Yeah,
yeah mostly like all the ABC tables are
same for June 1 and June 2.
But June 1 is using very few tables.
But we are using almost all the tables
except file related ones.
They're using batch metadata,
job metadata and batch run stretch,
job run stretch and job error stress.
I think these 5 tables only that we're
using is what I understand,
but we're using few other tables also.
OK moving on to next scheduling mechanism.
We are using Stone branch as scheduling
tool and load schedule time.
These these need these two needs to be
updated once we get the scheduling
details of of the job in stone branch.
So far now we are populating some dummy
values into our batch metadata table.
Upon we upon we get the actual load
scheduling times,
we have to update these two values in the
batch metadata table OK and audit create
date, time, audit created by user ID,
audit update by user ID,
audit update by user ID.
All these fields should be populated.
This is like these would be a current
timestamp,
current UTC timestamp values and these
would be the service account and key or
columns.
This is related to June 1, OK.
And then come moving on to the next table,
job metadata,
it will have all the details related to
jobs.
That's one second.
So key arguments,
this is like this will not be required
for us, correct?
For zone 2, Zone 3,
we don't require this column, OK?
And how do we like insert entry to this
table metadata table in Aurora?
No no no I mean like is there a script or
like it is manual like how?
How do we do it?
We are doing manually but what we were
told during collocation works.
There would be a new database set up for
ABC tables in Aurora because earlier
database name is not as per the standard.
So once we are pointing to the new
database setup which was built by liquid
base which was built through liquid base
of when we started using it.
All the DML process should be happen
through liquid base only.
As of now we are doing manual entries.
OK,
as of now we are doing manual entries but
we have one excel sheet so far CC where
we are we are handling one.
We are having one excel sheet which is
having the concat formula.
Using that we are creating the insert
statement.
I can show you that just for reference.
Isn't it like generic statement or only
for applicable for CC?
It can be user by all.
Yeah, it can be used by all.
But for a CC who I have created because
this is the first build.
So like this is the first I said that I'm
working on the build, right.
So for this for easy setup I have created
this.
It can be leveraged for others as well.
So if you see batch metadata here,
whatever the insert script which would be
here with all the table names,
sorry with all the column names and then
we have batch anyway batch ID is auto
increment value.
We don't need to provide value for that.
So whatever the values that needs to be
provided, I just kept here.
So you can just copy this and make a new
new entry and for the new batch you just
need to update the values batch ID,
batch name, batch description,
active flag, e-mail ID, source name,
domain name, application layer name,
dependency name whatever that needs to be
updated.
I have added these here and here.
In this you just need to update the
source related information.
I told you right.
So here batch ID source source,
application source batch ID it is a batch
ID value from batch metadata table which
is related to John one right?
And this batch ID is also a auto
increment value.
We might have different value in other
environments.
So we are creating this entries in such a
way that we can use the same DML
statements in any environment by just
updating the database name.
Anyway we are not also using the database
name in the query also I think it it
won't we are just using the schema name.
So this can be leveraged to any
environment as well.
So here we have just used this concat
formula and if I copy this to PARA you
can see so it just prepared one insert
script for me.
I just need to update all the values
according to the columns.
This is the source name column which is
there.
So that is like the table name or the
like,
just in which source name it is a source
name.
For example for CCO,
so CCO is the source name,
you will get 2 and like you will get that.
It's more of a functional area.
So we are getting for CCO account account
and contractor 2 domain two data domains
OK in CCO.
So what I got to know from gayathri CCO
is the source name and domain name is the
account for account.
So we have similar document even for
contract.
So there we have added all the entries
related to contract domain.
So here we have kept contract as the
domain name OK application layer name.
As of now we are doing two data domain
layer of zone 2.
Zone 2 is the target zone.
Here there are two layers one is dated
domain and the other one is functional
area.
Something I don't remember the exact name
we have.
No we are doing 2 domain level.
So application layer name is dated domain.
In case if we are leveraging the same
framework to any other layer to any other
zone,
we have to update the entry based upon
that.
OK.
And then moving, if you want,
I can share this document with you so
that like if anybody anywhere it is in
SharePoint only we can live with this.
Yeah, you can, you can share the link.
Yeah, Yeah, I'll share everything.
OK.
And then coming,
are we good on batch metadata?
Can we move on to the next table?
Yeah.
So job metadata.
So here we'll have information related to
two jobs for each batch for each batch.
OK, so if we go through,
if we get into the details of column,
first one is job ID which is a primary
key column for this table and it is a
auto increment value and then job name,
it is similar to batch name and batch
metadata.
So here also we will be providing the
details related to the job, job,
job source, source name,
domain name and then target table name
and last load.
That's it.
This is the format that we have to follow
for job Job description.
I may have gone wrong.
Let me get it from here.
I think this is the job description we
have to follow.
This is Mr here job to load broker party
address from CMPM In this this is how we
have to pass the job description.
OK then is active flag.
It is also refers to the same whether the
job is active or not.
So if we want to deactivate any job loads
during rerun or restart.
If we want to deactivate anything we can
just directly make it inactive.
This also I I'll show whether how this is
active function like column we are using
whenever we are running a specific job
task.
OK and batch ID whatever the batch ID to
which this job is linked then that batch
ID we have to populate here and target
target table name, target schema name,
target database name and target load type
type 0 type 1, type 2,
append only and workflow name.
This is the job workflow name.
So it has to follow the same format like
similar,
similar thing like similar or what it
says standard.
So TSTSKFL load broker is the data domain
source source to target.
So this is how it it should follow the
naming convention and wrap so.
So this database names, human names,
table names.
So add this like there must,
this must be parameterized in the
mappings, right?
Are you,
are this taken from here or from
parameters?
No, no, no, no.
It is a batchman.
It is a metadata table, right?
We have to populate them.
We have to populate them from here only.
OK, so,
so these are like those parameters will
be populated from here only.
They're like this will not be.
So actually the intention behind having
these database name and schema name of
the target table is to have to use these
in job post load,
job post load while calculating the
counts and all right.
So whenever if we are updating the
database name,
schema name for this table anytime we
have to update the entry even in job
metric data like while we are updating
anything in parameter file,
we have to update the same here also
because we are using parameter file also
this these are there like table names
Yeah like for for our stage load and
stage 2 main load we are use we have
already parameterized database Newman
scheme and for the target table yeah we
are we have done that.
But these are directly being instead of
like instead of having the parameters
passage from the stage load to job post
load.
Every time we are having this,
we are like we have already columns in
place in this table, right?
So we are leveraging them for job post
load.
OK.
So I mean if I note on this,
maybe we can discuss,
you know doing the job OK and wrapper
workflow name.
This is the batch task flow name and
count threshold indicator and amount
threshold indicator.
So this count threshold indicator is
related to any check that needs to be
like for any particular column.
If we need to do a diction count check on
source and target,
then we have to mark it as Y,
otherwise it can be kept as N.
And here I'm on balance check indicator
is nothing.
But if we want to check any by amount
column aggregated sum between source and
target,
then they will make it as by else it can
be can OK.
And and this this cheques related details
right on which column it should be there.
So there should be there a different
metadata table for that as well, right?
Correct.
Yeah,
these two related to the balance
reconciliation,
we just need to mark the indicator column
here so that that particular balance
reconciliation would be provided like
will be executed.
So otherwise if these are N,
then why do we need to do that table,
that particular component execution?
We don't need it, right?
We can skip it and we can also get all
the details related to a table using look
by just looking at this.
OK.
And then all these are audit columns.
After that we have key arcs.
It is relevant to zone 1 and source to
target layer is it's we are just doing a
load from refined to zone to data domain
layer.
So whatever the source that we have,
it is zone one, right?
So I was told to have them source to
target layer as refined to zone to data
domain.
So I followed.
So it will be it will be like same for
all zone one zone 2 tables,
zone 1-2 zone two data domain.
So in zone 2 we have two layers right?
1 is a data domain and the other one is
some functional area something is there.
So there are two layers in one in in zone
2 so far zone 1-2 zone two data domain
load.
We can use refine to zone two data domain.
OK,
how do we know like if it is data domain
or the other functional areas?
Yeah, I, I,
I ask like it's more of a functional
thing,
like it's a more of a data model area.
So I asked for broker account,
I asked them,
they told data like we are first loading
to all their domains.
So that is the reason why we have
populated the same source to target layer
for both broker and account and contract
domains of CCO.
So we have you asked zone 1,
I asked SPY about this.
OK,
so if we are taking up any other any new
asset, right,
we we need this information whether it
has to be populated like this or not.
One is data domain and other value is
what?
What?
For the other one it is just source layer
and target layer.
So source layer is John 1 only.
But spym asking me to keep it as refined
because in some other John one team or
some other team we saw they are calling
that John 1 as refined.
So so I'm asking me to keep this.
So I kept this like this,
kept it like this.
OK, OK.
And this one you said this is data domain.
That's why we put it as data domain,
right?
And another category is also there.
So for that, what will be the value?
So you're asking about the other layer in
June 2, right?
I'm not sure on the exact name of it.
But what I'm thinking is functional area
is the other layer in the June 2
functional unit.
Functional area you think in our code for
this particular point we are we are not
reached to that point like we're not
currently working on the functional area.
So I'm not sure on this details area.
You can check with fire ones about that
other layer in June 2.
OK, I don't have the details of sorry.
And if you see here we have similar like
excel document for for job also where we
can make all the queries like which can
be leveraged across all environment using
this.
So here we are using batch metadata so we
have to populate our corresponding batch
batch ID right here.
So that is pulled using this query like
by looking into this batch metadata using
source name, domain name,
application and this so nowhere the
primary keys like we we planned in a such
a way that nowhere the primary keys of
any other table should not be populated
as hardware values.
They should be driven by query no.
So we planned that when we created this
document,
you can leverage the document for job
metadata.
OK,
so I have to change this philtre parts
everything to generate Yeah,
you just need to take a copy of this and
just copy it.
And you have to just change whatever the
column that I have given here with
whatever the columns that I have in job
description is that to flag batch ID will
be always batch ID.
Because here in this column,
in this from clause column we are
updating the source name, domain name,
all these things, right.
So you can keep batch ID as it is.
But you have to update this from close
column and table name, schema name,
database name should be updated and load
type workflow name,
wrapper workflow name should be updated
and count threshold value and indicator
and amount balance check indicator should
be updated as per the functionality of
the table and audit columns.
You can use the same formulas like same
functions they will work.
And I'm providing null to key ox as it's
just a as it's it's a column related to
and source to target layer.
This is also same for all these tables.
So I kept it like this.
So here they have given 1/2 data domain.
OK I have to check on this thing.
This has to be refined TO12 data domain.
I'll check I'll update.
I'll update it.
OK, OK.
And then moving on to the next table ETL
data injection metadata.
So here we have our zone 2 tables has
dependency on zone 1 table loads.
So we are having a separate Table 2
populate sourcing window which can be
used in our actual table OK as batches.
At very high level we are trying to have
this ETL data injection metadata like ETL
data injection source window table
runtime.
It's a runtime table we are keeping at
our job level so that every job will have
different source table and it might have
one or more source table.
So all those sourced table lettered
information would be first kept in the
ETL data ingestion metadata.
Based upon this the entrance would happen
in the ETL data ingestion metadata,
ETL data ingestion source window table.
But that logic wise information I'll give
it whenever we are working on that job
preload part OK, one, three.
But you mentioned that for one job there
could be multiple sources.
What do you mean by that?
So in June 2,
for any target table there can be chance
of having multiple source tables.
That means June 1 tables right?
So then there would be.
Then we have to provide sourcing window
for each and every table.
OK, so this particular for for,
for such cases in job metadata table they
will there will be one entry for one
target table, right,
One entry for one table.
Yeah, in OK, in job metadata table,
we'll have only one entry that is for our
target table.
Here in ETL data ingestion window,
it depends the entries depends upon the
number of source tables that that the
target holds that the target has.
OK.
So basically this is source label table,
source label data table source, correct?
They stores ETL ingestion configuration
details,
included source table and target table
and batch hub active status and audit
information.
It is used by the ETL framework to
determine which source source tables
would be ingested into corresponding
target tables for a given job and batch.
OK,
first we'll give the target batch ID a
target job ID and target table.
So target batch ID.
So target batch ID,
target job ID from where we'll be getting
it,
We'll be getting it from the batch
metadata table and target job ID,
we will be getting it from the job
metadata table.
I'll show you the query how how we are
populating it in the Excel sheet and then
target table name, source name,
source source name,
source table name and ezat to and then
audit field.
That's it.
OK, let me show you the sample query.
So here if you see sales representative
I'm bringing batch ID and job ID from the
batch and job metadata tables.
So here I have the from Clausner.
So here I'm getting I'm doing a join
between these two tables and I'm bringing
job ID,
batch ID based upon these source domain
name, application name,
target zone and job name.
So based upon this part is hard coded,
right?
Every time like we have to change
according to this value the same column,
yeah,
the same column should be should be
updated because these values would be
different, different,
different from table to table, right.
So based upon our table,
we have to there's the value needs to be
updated.
Yeah, yeah.
So batch ID, job ID, table name.
So I have just explicitly given that they
will understand where this BM will come
and they won't miss this from close
updation, right?
That's why I explicitly mentioned these
like this.
So they'll see this alias name and
they'll get it, right?
That's the reason why.
And target table name,
source name is CCO and source table name
active indicator and audit fields.
OK if you see for agreement there are
around 6 tables, six source tables.
So for each source table they have made
an entry.
So similarly we have to make an entry if
we have multiple source tables.
So the intention behind this is each
table will be loaded or complete.
Each table's load might be completed at
different points of time and each table
and also zone 1.
How zone 1 works is if any one of the
tables load is failed it will mark the
status as partial.
If all the table load is completed then
partial batch status OK in batch run
stats if any one of the tables load is
failed then it will mark it as partial.
If all the table loads is failed then it
will mark as failed.
If all the tables load is completed
successfully then it will be marked as
completed.
So how our zone 2 works right?
If my zone 1 batch status is either
partial or completed then go and start my
zone zone 2 batch OK.
In this way if any one of our source
table load gets failed then we should not
process without target table load right?
So for that purpose and also each source
table will will be loaded at different
times right?
We we are not sure based upon the run
order it will be loaded in the source.
So based upon that we have to fetch the
like the source job and time of each
source table so that based upon the
source window will be fetched.
OK OK so so batch label status I got it
that we are getting partial.
So suppose 2 jobs failed and three jobs
got successful right?
And here in total 5 jobs are there five
source tables are there basically right.
So in that case like how,
how my data will be loaded,
all the five tables will be considered or
is that any?
No that Yeah, so I got your question.
So if any one of the source table load is
failed,
then we won't proceed with the target
table load.
We'll just send out a message stating
that the one of the source tables load is
not completed successfully.
So we are not proceeding well.
So basically in that case,
like if batch status is partial,
then we're not loading the data, right?
We're just sending a notification.
Oh wait,
if the zone 1 status is partial or
completed, OK, let let me clear you.
This zone one job run stats will have
only two statuses either completed or
failed.
It won't have partial OK,
but batch will have failed partial and
completed.
Our zone 2 is dependent on zone 1 batch,
so we are proceeding with our zone 2
batch run.
If my zone 1 batch run status is either
partial or completed there there might be
chances of having my source table failure
in that batch run or might not be.
If my source table is failed during the
zone 1 batch run which I'm considering
for my batch to for my zone to batch run
then I have to like stop my target table
load,
batch the target so so while loading the
data then in that case we are taking the
job status as well for each sources right
for zone 1 correct?
Correct.
We will be doing it as part of ETL data
ingestion source window load.
Just like batch run starts preload,
job run starts preload,
we'll have a component ETL the transition
source window load for different
scenarios.
We'll get one to it later when we are
going to the code letters then it would
be more clear for you.
But as of now just understand this.
We're using this table for that purpose.
And here in the batch metadata,
we're just giving the source details for
our target, OK.
And this has to be in in such a way that
how they are making entries in their job
metadata.
So for each of these tables,
we have entries in job metadata which are
made by June 1 team during their
development, right?
How they are making their entries for
this particular table we have to make the
similar way.
OK similar table name should be there
because we are do using this column to
compare against the entries and the job
metre data.
OK fine moving on.
So we should be following the job metre
data table entries for zone 1 for this of
June 1 for populating this source table
name because I see one discrepancy NCCO
the source table name is CCO DB_scoop
one_sales Rep code.
But they are using just sales Rep code T
as their source table name there.
But they are loading but they are
actually loading CCO DB scoop one table
only using the job metric data entry.
So based upon that I made the same tree.
OK, And then moving on to job rule master.
So what is a?
It is a job rule master table which will
have all the validation rules.
So it will just hold all the validation
rules which can be applied to any job.
Before applying assigning any job rule,
any rule that if we want to apply any
rule to any of the table,
first entry should be made in this job
rule error master if it is not already
present.
So for example,
null check is one of the one of the rule
that we want to do for any of for one of
my table,
then I have to make an entry about this
null check and its scope.
That's it.
We just need to is it?
Is it?
It is how like is it table level details
or no, it is not table level.
It is column level validation rule.
So if we're if I'm using the same,
if I'm doing null check for table one,
I'll be using the same rule ID.
If I'm doing so,
I'll I'll explain the job rule assignment
also.
Then you'll get an understanding.
For now just take it as a rule master
table which will hold all the rules and
it's rule scope that's it.
Rule IDs is the prior to increment value,
rule name is null check and rule scope is
column OK.
So this is the rule if I want another
rule like length, data size OK.
If I want to do a length check of a
column then I do I'll make an entry with
the rule name as length check and I'm
doing it for a column.
So rule scope is column that's it.
We just need to use make entries like
this.
OK, coming on to the next table.
I'll, I'll come to this table again.
Job rule, assignment table.
What was the assignment job rule master
table assignment.
The above 1 is job role master.
This is job role assignment.
And the entry like OK,
so that is a that table is a basically
the generic entry, right?
With all that unique kind of validation
types, yeah, it's a generic entry.
I'll tell you about this job rule
assignment table,
then you'll get a clearer picture and
difference between these two tables.
So job rule assignment table,
it assigns the validation rules to jobs.
So here we are assigning job means our
table load, right?
So whatever the rules that we want to
assign for our table,
we have to make entries in this table.
So first is this is this is static table
or this is a run table,
static table only you you'll get you will
understand it once I complete this you'll
understand it.
First.
Let me go through the column description
then we'll see if you still have any
questions.
OK, first this is primary key column.
It is just auto increment value and
validation type that is pre, pre or post.
So we are doing doing the validation
before loading into the target.
So that is the reason why we kept test
pre.
So is this column used somewhere or just
for knowledge?
It is just just for information purposes.
OK.
And then target column name,
this is the end broker party address.
I want to do a null check for this broker
party ID.
So I did I kept that column name.
Target column name is pattern available.
And so we are not using any pattern.
So we are implementing the DQ validation
check within the ETL logic only.
I'll let you know when we are discussing
about the but the like what is this
pattern valuable thing?
I mean like what can I do?
It's like is what I'm thinking here is if
we have any pattern.
So if I'm I'm checking, I'll check, right?
So I what I'm thinking is it's,
it can we can provide some expression
here so that we can use the same
expression directly in detail logic to
perform the DQ check like that.
I'm I'm thinking otherwise if we are
taking I, I,
I don't know particularly about this
column like particular significance of
this column.
But we,
it is we are not using this column much.
So I'm keeping it as N.
But what I'm thinking is even if we are
using for a date column,
there would be some particular pattern if
we're we're using right so far that also
we might be using this for information
purpose is what I'm thinking.
But make a note of it.
We can get this from I don't know,
we are not using this.
So this is for information purpose only
or like it can be?
Yeah,
it's it's for as of now as per our
implementation,
these two are just information purpose
and we are not using these columns in
June 2 as of now as per the framework,
we are not using them.
That's why I kept it as end for pattern
available and pattern as well.
OK.
And coming to RSCVRT code, it can be IRC.
OK here I have just provided the sample
value.
I see.
So there are two kinds of error errors
here,
informational error and critical error.
So if we mark any DQ check as critical,
if it gets failed then we should not make
entry and we should not insert that
recording to our target table.
We should route that recording to our job
role.
Hey,
so that is applicable only for that
record or in that data set only one
record that record.
So if if any record fails this critical
validity check then it should not be
entered into the target table.
It should be routed to edit timetable and
if any record that fails if it is marked
as informational check.
If any records fails an informational
check then it should be routed both to
both target table and job role.
Added detail table OK in case of
information come again.
The last OK if any rule that if any rule
assigned to a particular column is marked
as informational and if any record fails
that information I'll check then the
record should be populated to both target
table and job rule assignment,
job rule errors error detail timetable.
Because here we it is marked as
information with the client is the client
doesn't have any issue if if it is loaded
to target,
but they just need that information that
this particular issue is there for this
particular tech call.
So it will load that record,
but it will make mark it as and it will
also load loads this record into error
detail table.
So we will make we'll use this column to
send out the notification and also so
error table as well as target table,
correct.
And for null cheques error message text
it's just generic null values found like
that.
So if we for now, so error message,
it is generally it will be taken from
here will be Yeah, like for null values,
we are just populating null values from
and for other cheques as when I mean we
are found only will be taken.
Yeah,
we don't have any like template for any
other cheques as of now.
We are just checking null cheques only
for all the for all the tables in ADW
producer and Sysu.
I said we haven't come across any new
check.
In case if we have any new check in
future,
then we have to think about this error
message text.
How should it be populated?
OK.
And he's had to flag it's just active
state of the rule assignment, create data,
all these are all it collapse and CD.
Can you scroll up just to move is active
like what?
What does it do?
Is that fixed it?
If we yeah, if we don't want any rule,
then we can deactivate this rule here.
And also as we are implementing the rules
in the ETL logic there also we have to
update in the logic also we have to go
and remove that particular logic.
So it will not take the indicative help
from here.
It will not so that you mapping yeah,
yeah we have implemented it in within the
ETL logic.
We we didn't make it reusable like
automatic phone within the stage load
mapping only how we have done earlier in
AMIC, right.
So similar way we have implemented within
the so the entire table table is like
will not be like be used by our code.
Just this is just for information and
purposes it yeah,
if we are deactivating any rule here,
we have to deactivate it here.
And also the logic which is there in the
course should also be revised based upon
this.
OK.
And another thing.
So suppose I, I,
I have like 3 different kind of
validation cheques right?
For, for the table.
So in that case,
like is it like automatically from here
we'll be fetching what kind of cheques
are there or manually just we have to
check on this table manually?
We are checking manually.
We are checking just same like I mean
I'll I'll show you that whenever we have
that session right on download,
everything is manual there and we are
keeping it manual only as per Nitika and
that's why I'm guidance.
I just kept it manual only got it OK and
audit columns and then rule ID.
So here I'm applying null check.
I'm doing null check for my column.
So what is the rule ID for null check in
my job role Master 1.
So if I'm using so this null check then I
have to apply add that rule ID here and
corresponding job ID here.
So if I job ID from where I'm getting
from job metre data, job,
job metre data table only.
OK, OK.
So like whenever if I want to do a new
rule,
then I have to make an entry into this
table 1st and then only I would be able
to assign that rule to any of my job.
So like there is a differential integrity
between this table.
Yeah, it would be there.
OK.
And also,
as the entry to null check is already
made made into this job rule master,
I can use the same rule ID to any of my
table wherever I'm using, wherever I want,
I'm using the null check.
So I have to add an entry in in this
assignment team.
I didn't.
That's it, That's it.
You don't need to make duplicate entries
into this job rule list.
So there will and it is just like a top
level table.
OK, so in supposing like two things.
So suppose yeah,
if I try to like enter similar kind of
like cheques in that of mustard table.
So will it going either I I don't I
didn't get to Could you please come again
to you?
Suppose I'm I'm trying to enter like null
check twice again, again again.
Yeah, I think it don't it don't it I, I,
I don't think it will give you an error,
but yeah, it won't.
I think it won't give you an error.
But it is not good practise to have
duplicate entries into that rule master
if it is already existing.
We have to just check whether our rule is
already existing in the rule master or
not.
And also I'll show you about this job
role master.
So job role master,
we have just this capitalist entry here.
So that it would be like just kept this
entry.
But we haven't used this entry because
this entry is already made for this.
OK, in job role master,
job role assignment,
we have this column right rule ID.
So we are getting this rule ID from job
role master.
JRM is job role master.
If you look at the if you look at this
from clause,
I'm using rule name and rule scope.
OK,
I mean based upon this I'm pulling the
rule AD if you if you see that it is
coming as null then you have to check the
rule master table.
If that is not made already then you have
to make entry here 1st and then so you
can use this rule in this table.
So if suppose there is like it is 123
rule ID, OK,
I'm trying to insert and it is not
present in Rule master table,
then it will show me that here if you are
trying to use a dummy value instead of a
true true rule rule ID, it will.
It will,
it will because they have a reference
every foreign to corresponding primary
key.
Yeah, that's it.
And then moving on to the batch metadata,
sorry, balance reconciliation metadata.
So this assigns a balance reconciliation
at source and arbit level 2 jobs.
OK.
So whatever the balance sheet that we
want to perform to our table level
columns, target table level columns,
we'll we'll make an entry here, OK,
balance,
balance reconciliation metric ID is the
primary key column.
It is out incremental value.
It's that increment value is missing.
So these are like builded to you ready
only.
No, no these are big end columns.
It it will be just auto incremented.
They're using this function auto
increment in the detail.
Oh, OK, got it.
And this is the description.
We just need to follow this description
reconcile distant count of this column
from June one source to June to target.
So if we are doing any amount check then
reconcile aggregate.
So there are five different cheques then
five different entries will be there or
once the entry with different different
no, no, no.
If there are five different cheques on
five different columns of a target of a
same target table,
then five entries has to be made OK
Similarly if we have 5 different 5
different table,
5 different columns the for which we are
doing a null check,
then we have to make 5 entries in the job
real assignment table same one second.
Can you repeat again.
So here if you see for this, OK,
let me show you for this job agreement
financial derived derived detail of
agreement,
agreement load agreement rating plan.
OK,
so you are saying Raghu's assignment
table is column table.
So if for the same table,
if there are five different columns for
which I need to do the last check there.
So 5 for entries should be yes.
OK.
So here also five entries will be needed.
And in the balance check also five
entries also.
Yeah,
based upon the functionality we have to
make the entries.
So here in agreement rating plan,
I have DQ cheques for these two columns.
So I made two entries for this.
OK, got it.
And balancing type is count here,
it can be either counter amount depending
upon the functionality we have to keep
and close to target and we'll confirm
this.
What kind of data cheques will be there?
What kind of balance cheques will be
there for the target table, correct?
Yeah, we'll confirm this.
Yeah.
So whoever working on the functional
analysis of the asset,
they should be ideally conforming this
based upon the current existing code,
because they're doing reverse engineering
based upon the current existing code,
right?
And if they have any balancing balance
reconciliation implemented in the
existing code,
the same cheques should be implemented
even in our future code, no,
if there is no balance reconciliation
happened.
But still,
if we have any amount column in the in my
future state table, target table,
then we have to do this,
perform this balance reconciliation for
that particular amount column, OK?
Even though there is no balance
reconciliation happened for this
particular column in the current state,
OK.
And what if the the balance
deconciliation fails for a column like
will it load the data or will it provide
later?
Like we have a threshold concept like
that.
I'll give you complete details that in
the whenever we are discussing the code
implementation.
But here I'll tell you, OK.
So target database name,
target schema name,
target table name and target column name,
region, source path, source query,
target query we are not choosing them.
OK,
OK we have all this logic implemented
reusable which is reusable for all tables
in the logic only.
I'll explain you there you get threshold
type is we can give either value or
percentage and threshold value and ease
active flag.
So coming to your question,
if my source and target amount aggregated
sum is completely balanced then my load
would be successful.
My job load is marked as complete.
If these aggregated sum is not is out of
balance but within the threshold value
which I have provided in the balance
reconciliation metadata,
then my job is successful.
But I'll send a notification notification
stating that this balancing metric is out
of balance and but within threshold.
OK,
a warning notification would be sent out
just like and one information check.
Got it.
And one more question.
So suppose this particular calculation,
right,
If it is within actual limit or not.
So is it directly applied in the code
itself?
It will do automatically or correct?
It will be applied in the code itself.
We just have to OK,
we just have to provide this column names
and all then it will automatically do
that calculation, correct?
Job post load, is it job post load?
Yes, we have to provide few things.
I'll let you know how,
where we have to provide in parameter
file and in parameter file only.
Mostly we have to provide.
I'll show you that during the clock code
implementation discussion.
And is that this flag is also used in the
code itself.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If we disable this here,
then this balance reconciliation check
won't be executed.
We don't need to make any change in the
code.
We just need to deactivate this.
That isn't OK.
So here itself or in the code also here
itself.
Here itself, here itself,
because the code is reusable and
automatic for balance reconciliation.
So we can deactivate here itself that
then it would be taken care in the code
based upon this value.
But for error one,
we need to do it manually,
do it both in both code and metadata.
Got it.
OK.
And audit columns and the corresponding
job ID.
So for this,
I don't have this in CCO because we don't
have any.
No.
Yeah.
Job ID is basically not a runtime ID,
right?
Job ID and batch ID are fixed, fixed,
right?
Correct.
OK,
these are similar to application master
ID and job master ID, clear.
Got it.
So I will get this value also using from
job metadata table only using the job
name and batch AD.
I don't have the entry in CCO but I'll
give you the entry which I was used
earlier.
However, during my testing I used this.
So I'll give you that sample entry so
that you can use that entry.
OK, OK.
Description of right?
I don't know it is taking more than an
hour just to give the high level.
Also we can just extend up to 2 and we
can close it reminding we will high level
will will take time right?
It is the overall OK and the description
of ABC runtime tables.
So whatever the runtime tables that would
be loaded during the batch or job run or
we can discuss them now batch run stretch
table.
So this will stores round level
information for batches.
OK.
And so we'll have a batch ID.
This is the foreign key column,
this is the batch ID column which would
be which we would get it from the batch
metadata table.
This the population of all the columns in
the runtime tables in all the runtime
tables would be there in the IDMC code
only and how we will be fetching the
batch ID.
So all those things,
all those things if we can discuss it
tomorrow or yeah, but in a high level,
I'm telling you in June 2,
we would be using those 4 columns.
I told you right, Source name,
domain name,
application layer and target June and is
that to Philtre also that is common.
But these four are you know different for
different tables and assets, right?
So we would be mainly using these 4
columns to fed the batch ID.
But all these logics would be present in
the ETL logic.
So tomorrow when we are going through the
code, we can discuss it.
But on a high level I'll tell you
everything.
OK.
And execution run ID it is the unique
identifier for the batch execution run ID.
So this execution run ID we will be using
in, in,
in all the tables OK to like have the
like to have the link between the runtime
tables.
So this is common in all the tables in
almost all the tables.
So one question.
So for batch one,
this execution ID is kind of like batch
ID from Amit and there will be separate
job ID, job run ID as well.
So here we have what like in emic compare
the batch ID with this execution run ID.
But we have another column called batch
run ID in this table which is the primary
key of this table.
I'll tell you why we are using a separate
execution run ID.
This is ID is useful for restart purpose.
So whenever we are doing a restart the
same execution run ID would be for
restart OK.
So but batch ID that thing will be batch
run ID, batch run ID,
batch run ID would be different because
every time every time when it makes an
entry it will be new.
But for a restart we would be using same
execution run ID.
So we just suppose just one one question.
So suppose today batch this particular
batch fails OK and the execution run ID
is 123 OK then like then tomorrow if I
restart again the execution and item will
be 128 same OK the next day suppose it is
successful 456 right?
So there will be no entry.
Then again suppose some 678 there is a
job batch failure right?
So then again next day it will be 678
like 678 OK.
So it will change according to each run.
So one particular instead said it will be
it is not like every time it will be only
yeah.
So here we have batch prerequisite
concept also yeah,
where we are checking whether my previous
previous zone to batch 1 is successful or
not.
So I'm working on this broker load, OK,
broker load batch.
So in the pre requisite part.
So in a regular basis.
So that load will be scheduled every time,
right?
So every time it will go and check
whether my previous load is successful or
not.
If it is successful then only it will
trigger my actual batch task flow OK.
If it is not successful it will send out
a notification stating that this is not
successful.
That's why we are not starting OK.
In case of any restart we know we will go
to know that this batch is not successful
and notification would be send out right
then.
In that case from the stone ramps will
directly trigger the batch task flow not
the not the batch prerequisite task flow.
So in this case whenever a batch run
previous batch run like latest batch run
is is in failed status then our code will
be like code is written in such a way
that if my latest batch run is failed
then consider it as a restart and do a
make an entry with the same execution run
ID into my batch run stats table.
So that would be passed on and also
execution run type would be restart.
So based upon this job run start job in
job run stats whatever the entry so all
the completed.
So here also whatever the table loads
that are completed in the previous load
won't be reprocessed OK.
Only the tables that are failed would be
reprofessed again and the same entry,
whatever the entry with the failed status
would be used for the new run like for
the restart run.
So there would be OK.
So when we restart,
so when we restart then the in the
previous execution run ID whatever job
was successful,
it will not trigger it again.
Only the failed search,
it will trigger correct just like in it.
OK, OK, yeah.
And then instance ID, database name,
table name,
these are optional fields for June 2,
June 3.
So we're not choosing them.
And so as in starting,
so this will be populated just taking the
so sourcing start.
And so this is different for different
execution types.
So here we'll have different execution
types.
So this would these values would be
different.
I'll tell you how these values would be
different for different execution types.
OK,
I'll tell you that later tomorrow when
tomorrow we are discussing about batch 2
loads, right?
So we we can detailedly discuss them,
but we are not using these for regular
loads,
regular incremental loads check we are
not using these sourcing statum and in
time for our incremental pull fetch of
the records from source.
We,
we are using this for few exceptional
scenarios.
I'll tell you what are the exceptional
execution scenarios.
So and then we can for that to like
identify for which yeah, it is there,
it is there.
But I told you that for history catch up
incremental,
we would be making manual entries into
batched and stats that design is not is
not included.
Apart from that,
for other scenarios it is already
implemented 3K and incremental.
It is first time increment,
first time increment.
So for the first time,
for the very first time how when we are
trying to get the data from June 1 and
June 1 is also getting the data from the
actual.
So this age very for the very first time
it is not implemented,
but for from the second time onwards,
what however,
the regular load is happening,
it was handled already.
And also restart scenario, rerun scenario,
zone 1 rerun scenario,
all these scenarios are already held.
OK, we'll get into deep details tomorrow.
Like tomorrow we have this patch preload,
right?
I'll try to expand each and every
execution type and what is pending also
I'll give you all the details.
And if we have any questions about the
pending design, we can reach out to also.
OK,
today let's complete the runtime tables
and we can close this call from tomorrow
onwards.
I'll tell the each and every step,
each and every phase details in RLD first
and I'll try to explain the code logic.
OK.
And then this batch start time end time
or just like during the batch preload,
this value would be populated with the
current time strong value.
And during the batch post load,
this value will would be populated with
the current time strong value,
just like in a mic.
And this yes,
those are just to use by 6 data or
something from my team only, right?
That's it.
Yeah,
they are using current time strong value
at UTC.
So we we are told to use the value a time
zone UTC only for any daytime value,
a date value in any of the ABC tables.
So we are directly using it from the
Aurora.
So we have a function the current time
stamp at duty CE function.
So we are leveraging that function for
populating these values and status would
be and preload.
It would be like while making an entry it
is taken as started.
Once it is based upon their batch run,
it would be either updated to completed
or failed.
OK so here you can see these three are
the values expected for this column and
source batch execution run ID.
It is nothing but the execution run ID of
the source batch source batch.
So here if you take CCO for example,
CCO will have one batch ID which is
called 387.
OK.
So whatever the latest execution run ID.
So during that run also there would be an
entry into my batch run stats, right?
So whatever the execution run ID that
that my source batch ID is holding,
that latest execution run ID would be
populated here and that is implemented
within the batch load code reload or
somewhere correct?
Correct.
It is implemented and this photo audit
columns batch rerun flag is Y&
Z and we have new flags as per the new
design.
HCIHY represents zone 2 rerun and
represents its regular run or restart.
Z represent zone 1 rerun and H represents
new values.
Are HCI OK?
H represent historical load,
C represent catch up load,
I represents incremental.
OK.
OK,
can you add this details in this site
description?
That is, no, it's OK.
Like you'll have those details at the
phase level clearly for each and every
execution type.
But for now, you can have this here.
OK.
And then extra,
this is relevant to zone 1.
And this is the bash one ID which is PK
column which is which would be populated
using UVID function and schema name is
not not it is relevant to zone one.
We are not using it.
OK, we are good, right.
We're going on to the job run starts.
Hello.
Yeah, yeah.
In job run Strat,
we'll have details about the job
execution.
So job run ID,
this is the primary key of this of this
table execution run ID.
I told you right,
it is a common field across tables.
So whatever the execution run ID that we
have in the batch run Strat,
same execution run ID could be populated
here.
For this particular batch run and job
instance ID, it is null.
It is relevant to the June 1 and job ID
is 258 but it is coming from the job
metadata table.
Job starting is the current timestamp
value which is populated at the job
preload and job end time is the current
timestamp value at UTC and which is
populated in the job post load state this
it will hold started completed and fail.
I will have started status in the job
preload after the load.
Based upon the run,
it would be either updated to fail or
completed.
Target table name, Target schema name,
target database.
These are just for informational purpose,
OK,
we're just populating them for
information and source.
Record count, target insert record count,
target update,
record count unchanged error as the name
suggests.
Like whatever the records that are
inserted into the target that are updated
into the target that remain unchanged
from the source to target and whatever
the record that I error inside unchanged
Excel, no change,
no change basically that was OK,
this is update and this is error.
This is whatever the record that error
route which was not loaded into the
target is this count and delete record
call delete record count.
We haven't faced any scenario as of now.
We are currently populating it as hard
code at zero.
That is what I got in.
But what is it?
I mean like is it like reject record?
So no, no it's not reject record.
It is like a record which is deleted in
my which is marked as deleted in my
source and that has to be either hardly
deleted from my target or soft deleted in
my target.
So we have a column Code audit delete
indicator whenever.
I don't know how they're handling this
delete scenario.
For now we are populating it as 0 but I'm
just giving you the details which we had
around this target delete record count at
that time.
So what they were thinking is whenever
any record is marked as delete that is
coming from the source and then we have
to mark this order delete indicator as
well.
And this is the approach of soft deleting
a record in our target table.
Otherwise if any record that is coming as
a delete in my source then we have to
hardly delete that from the target.
These two are the options that we have
and as we didn't come across any such
scenario in any of the assets currently
we have not like taken this up.
Whenever any such scenario comes in the
future,
we have to take it up and we have to
update the logic as per that.
Currently we are populating ******** AT0
to this count.
You mean like the job post load has also
might have to be changed if this logic
comes if it.
But if that scenario comes, yeah,
if that scenario comes, we have to OK,
so where is this order to be present in
all the targetables?
But I don't know the significance or how
that column would be would be populated.
The logic behind the logic used for that
column, I'm not sure on it.
We are currently populating N for that
particular column,
hard coded value N for that column,
it depends on the functionality area.
So just make a note of it.
So for this particular column,
there might be like things, right?
So make a note of we'll be able to guide
in that case.
Whoever working on the functional side,
they have to like they will raise this
question.
They have to raise this question.
So like they have to think of whether any
delayed scenario happening in their
current straight logic.
OK, if they have,
if they reach out to you,
then you have to ask reach out to Nitvika
or Swim because they are handling the
design.
So based upon the design logic,
we have to implement it in our ABC.
Swim or Nitvika would be the POC for you.
So first reach out to Swim.
If you if she asked you to go to Nilika,
then go to Nilika.
So first you should be It's fine.
OK.
Make all these things.
Yeah, like while we are daffing the mail,
right.
This would be helpful so that you you
will understand what needs to be revised
where needs to be revised in case any of
the issues come.
I'll left a mail in the evening.
Send out all the points to me so that
whenever any issue comes in any of the
philtre you you can just go through this
mail chain and you'll get the answer OK
and audit create date time or the all
these are audit columns.
Extra P is not related to us target RA
record count.
So here we are doing a referential
integrity.
So if my target table has any foreign key
target RA record count.
So this is related to referential
integrity.
So if my target,
if my target table is having any foreign
key and whenever I am looking upon my
parent table and then I don't find any
record for the business key that I'm
using from source,
then that record is marked as RA and it
would be routed to RA temp table OK And
from there we will get to know how many
records from source are move it to RA.
So this is the record count that would be
Oh, OK, OK,
so so it will count the records for which
in like for which the value is coming as
null for foreign.
Is it OK like for if it is null then it
will not you send the record, right?
Sorry I didn't get you come again.
No,
I'm not saying this concept of late
arriving records in.
Am I correct?
Late arriving record I'll add records
later.
Later I will record.
So for example,
while I'm loading my target table broker
party address.
So in my broker party address I have a
foreign key called broker party ID which
is coming from my broker party table.
First my source table of broker party
address is loaded OK and first OK first
my broker party table is source table is
loaded and it is moved and the data is
loaded to broker party table.
And then my bro when my broker party
table party address table source table is
loaded and the information is when
whenever this load from my broker party
address source to target is happening the
records there are few records for which
we don't find a corresponding broker
party ID in the broker party table might
be because of late arriving records in
its source table.
OK then in that case we are routing them
to the temporary table in the next so
those on the next day.
So those records will not be loaded into
the actual target table right target
table they won't be loaded into our
actual target table.
They would be routed to temporary table
and from temporary to main array.
On the next day we we will try to
reprocess whatever the records that fall
in the array.
So on the next day if if the my parent
table is already got loaded with these
records whatever routed to RA yesterday.
So if I'm able to found those record
those will be reprocessed again and they
would be loaded to target on the next day
on the day 2 and one those process day 2.
Also if it it doesn't come then then it
will be as it is if if it is already
processed 9 on day 2.
Whatever the records that I routed to
main table right I will mark them.
There is a flag called process flag while
I'm making inserts it its value is null.
Once I've once these records are
processed then I'll mark it as Y OK.
So in the next if if any one of the
record that is not processed on day 2
also.
But on day three,
if it gets processed like on day 2,
it will be kept as chase null only OK.
And on day three if it finds a match then
it will be processed to target and the
process flag would be marked as Y OK.
So it will check every day basically
every every day it will check for all the
RA requests.
Yes, we got it.
And this is this RA temp 2 RA main is
implemented by Bharat.
But they asked me to keep it as part of
job as it is a reusable component and it
will be it is RA referential integrity.
Referential integrity.
OK, OK got it.
So critical error check flag and
informational error check flag I told you
right there are critical cheques
information like on ballot.
So if there are any records that that
fail critical error then it will be
marked as N if there are no issues then
it would be marked as Y.
This same goes with this and here ballot
can check why we have only one right.
So if any check that where metrics are
out of balance and out of threshold,
then it would be marked as N otherwise it
it would be Y OK, OK.
And then coming onto ETL data ingestion
source window.
This window is user to define the
sourcing window for our for loading our
target table based upon the status of the
source.
It's a runtime table, OK.
It will be using the ETL data transitions
metadata table, job metadata table,
job run stats table,
all these tables to populate values in
this.
I'll tell you the details to like
whenever we're discussing this table load,
but but in a high level,
it will take the execution run ID of the
target which is nothing but the value
that which is populated during our batch
preload into our batch run stats, right?
The same execution run ID will be
populated here and my target batch ID
whatever the batch ID that our zone 2
batch has that would work with it and
target job ID same that would be getting
from the HID and job run ID whatever a
job run ID populated into my job run
stretch,
the same value would be populated here
Target table name,
source source table name.
So we'll get this 2 details from the job
ETL retaination metadata table and
corresponding job run ID, job status,
sourcing, start time sourcing, and depth.
So all these details,
all these three details,
we would be getting it from the job,
job run stash table.
I'll tell you how we would be getting the
values for these four.
OK, OK, tomorrow and job error stash.
So this is like a error log table.
Whenever our job load gets failed at any
step it we will make an entry into this
table.
We have to make an entry into this table
and here job error ID.
This is a primary key column UUID column
which will be generated using UUID and
job ID job run ID error type error code
and error message.
So.
So if if the like particular entry is
error, doubt, right?
So then only at entry will be populated
here and the other reports will be
populated to target at any instance.
At any instance.
If we are marking up a job or run stat
status as fail at any instance,
we have to make an entry into this table.
You'll get all the details whenever we
are doing that code implementation, right?
So even during job reload also we would
be making entry into this table whenever
our stage load gets failed.
Then we will be making whenever our mail
load get failed or whenever any one of
the job reload component or job post load
component gets failed,
we'll make an entry into this table.
You will get the details where exactly
this table would be populated whenever we
are getting to the code details only.
So here I'm given sample values.
So in case if my stage table load or
target table load gets failed then I have
to mark it as error execution, error,
job failed,
job run was failed during the load,
the corresponding job name, batch name,
job ID, job run ID.
I have to populate all these values in
the job error message.
These are hard coded or no, No,
these are not hard coded.
I'll I'll show you this part is hard
coded.
But what are the values are there?
Those would be like even the hard code,
this is not also hard coded.
Client asked us to have it in the static
parameter file.
So I kept it in the static parameter file.
I'll show you and all these error message
is hard coded.
It's a it's a parameterized only.
I'll show that to you and audit columns,
OK.
And then moving on to job role execution
log.
So this this stores each rules each.
So we have job role assignment table
where we will assign rules to our table,
target table columns, right?
So for each and every rule,
we will have an entry into this job role
execution log table during preload and in
the post load,
we'll get the stats of each and every
rule.
So for example,
these many records got So we have for
example, we assigned for two columns,
column one and column two,
we have assigned null check.
OK, so for for these two entries,
an enter would be made into this job rule
execution log during the preload and post
load.
How many,
how many records fail this particular job
rule,
job rule assignment ID that stats would
be there if everything went successful,
then only execution details will be there.
I'll, I'll go through the like,
I'll walk and the, the,
the reports which which we didn't like
which for this rule error, right?
So where like in which table are those
loaded?
That is job rule detail table,
job rule error detail table.
Job rule error detail table is different
here.
This is the extra table which we don't
find it in our previous project.
Job rule error table was the previous one
for job rule No no no job error.
That is also an extra extra table that
job error stats.
Is that the job level?
OK, job level,
job rule execution log is at the job rule,
job rule, assignment level,
job rule error detail is at the record
and column level details.
Yeah.
OK, you got it.
OK.
You will get the clarity.
Whenever we get into the code level
discussion, right?
We you'll get it.
You'll get the clarity.
So there is a different section for like
we we'll cover it as part of job job.
So job preload, job load, job post load,
these are lengthy topics to discuss job
batch preload and job job batch preload
also somewhat lengthy because of multiple
execution and a job post load is very
simple.
So we will adjust time in between so that
we can we plan to cover everything as per
the schedule.
OK so job if we go to this details of the
columns job rule,
execution and edit is the primary key.
Start time is just start time which will
be loaded as part of preload as current
execution,
current time stone value and end time
would be updated in the post load with
the current time stone value status.
It would be started initially and then
based upon the rules it would be the past
or fail OK Error message would be null if
in case if it is passed.
What was the table name for this one Job
rule execution bug and execution details
will be like 0 record with null values
found as it is passed.
So if if this will be paid will also be
like hard coded value or down for job
post load automatically.
This is like here if we if we don't find
the records in the job rule.
So you'll get it like this count whatever
we have this right.
This would be you know as per like this
implemented logically, I'll show you.
So if it is failed,
then a error message will have this
message and error execution details would
be null.
So it's vice versa based upon the status.
So this count.
So if it is passed, it will be always 0.
If it is failed,
this error message will have the exact
count of records for which this
particular job rule assignment ID is
failed.
So for one column,
one column and how how many records are
having the DQ issue for this particular
column,
one that will be recorded and how many
records that are failed that failed for
this particular column to check that will
be recorded.
OK and then coming to job will error
detail.
This is the detail where we have
previously OK job assignment ID OK, fine.
So OK, job will assignment ID,
this will get it from Yeah,
job will assignment table and job run ID
and then job will job will error detail
table.
This will store the details at record and
column level.
OK like we will load from So I in in the
job load we will load all the details at
the record level right into job rule,
error detail timetable.
From error detail time too we will
transpose the records and we will make
records at the record and column level.
You will get this understanding when we
are discussing the code.
But in in a high level source database
name, source schema name,
source table name, source column name,
source record identifier,
source error text or it fails.
These would be their rule,
rule assignment ID, execution and ID,
operating rule ID and severity put all
these would be populated.
I'll I'll tell you whenever.
So as these two tables error rule
execution and error rule with table or
something.
So these two like how how is it like is
it a manual process or No, no, no,
it is automatic.
It is automatic only.
Both of them are automatic only ETL logic
where we are doing this DK check rate
within the stage load,
that is not automated that is manual
thing and batch reconciliation stats.
So here also this is primary K column.
Valuation date is nothing but the date
for which balancing is done.
OK,
valuation rate like if you are doing the
dates today,
OK date for which balancing is done where
balancing can be blank if the scenario
does not exist, OK,
it's like a valuation date.
I'll show you at OK,
I'll I'll show you this area.
There is a like confusion on this column,
but I have implemented correctly in the
logic.
I'm not exactly like getting what is the
value that has to be populated.
OK, OK,
yeah I think this is something like if we
want to do a valuation for a particular
day then I think we have to populate it,
otherwise it can be null is what I got
from spam.
But I'll give you the exact detail when
we are discussing about this balance
reconciliation, OK,
Just make a note of it.
We'll,
we'll you can bring this whenever we are
discussing about balance reconciliation,
OK?
Source value, whatever source value,
target value, balancing flag,
out of balance value, threshold flag,
all these things you know already OK.
And if these are out within balance,
then if these are completely balanced,
if these two values,
then my balancing flag would be Y then
out of balance value.
If they if they if they are not same then
this out of value is greater than 0,
right?
And if the counts are within threshold,
then it would be Y otherwise it would be
N.
This flag would be N then audit fields
and balancing cancellation metric ID,
job run ID, aggregation run ID.
OK.
This would be getting from the balance
balance reconciliation matrication table.
And these two are from runtime tables.
OK.
And then Lucid chart.
So tomorrow for each phase wise,
I'll go I'll I'll walk you through each
phase in lucid chart and LLD and cool.
So everything would be aligned.
OK today.
Let's close this call.
Just check, go through this like station,
check schedule.
OK.
If you think like we'll need an
additional day or something,
then we can force them because there are
a lot of things I see like even from and
there are a lot of extra tables here as
well, which has to be covered, right?
So you will know it better.
So just go to the session.
Yeah.
So anyway,
we are planning to close it by 7th, right?
You would be on leave on 20th and 29th
only, right.
So 27th and 90th, Yeah, 27th and 20th.
Today's only.
No, Monday and Tuesday.
So we'll see if we are able to complete
it by 31st.
If not,
we'll extend one day or two even like
Swam has given you buffer, right?
So I would be available till 14th, OK.
If I have to extend day or one in the
like in the second week of August,
then that I can do like just like giving
how I'm giving you one hour every day in
this week, right?
I can give you one hour in that week also
mostly we'll try to like wrap this up in
the first week of August like one of our
is sufficient is what I'm thinking.
But if it is goes beyond that,
we'll check.
We'll inform Span.
Yeah, yeah.
Let me stop the recording.
Yeah, I'll.